Michael Braverman

DevOps/Systems Engineer

@ mbraverman96@gmail.com





Summary

I am an IT specialist who specializes in the field of DevOps while also being passionate about Python and Rust languages. My interests range from designing and building processes at the infrastructure and architecture level to diving into the most low-level areas. I enjoy solving interesting problems regardless their difficulty while constantly expanding my horizons throughout the process.

Experience

International HFT Hedge-Fund

2023-11 - Present

Systems Engineer

NDA

Quarta 2023-06 — 2023-11

DevOps Engineer / Platform Engineer

- Played a pivotal role in spearheading a comprehensive of our companies infrastructure revamp from its foundation, leveraging HashiCorp's Terraform, Consul, and Vault solutions;
- Orchestrated the integration of IaC and Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) methodologies through Azure DevOps (with an ongoing transition to a Kubernetes-powered GitLab CI + Argo CD setup), while harnessing the capabilities of Terraform and Ansible;
- Managed and implement Systems Reliability Engineering (SRE) and DevOps methodologies to oversee a comprehensive client
 infrastructure, encompassed nearly 100 virtual machines and involving the orchestration of various technologies including
 GitLab CI, Kubernetes, etcd, Minio, MetalLB, Dex OpenID provider, Consul, Vault, Prometheus, Grafana, Zabbix, ELK Stack,
 HAProxy (built from source), keepalived, Patroni, PostgreSQL and Clickhouse;
- Developed tools, such as an infrastructure diagram generator leveraging Ansible inventory: github.com/mbrav/ansible-inventory-diagram
- Curated and released publicly accessible images of up-to-date Docker image builds incorporating OpenSSL with GOST TLS encryption: github.com/mbrav/docker-gost

CentrInform 2022-11 – 2023-05

DevOps Engineer

https://center-inform.ru

- Configured Kubernetes components from scratch, diligently studying and implementing best practices;
- Engaged with technologies including Grafana, Prometheus, Apache Kafka, Nginx, Traefik, GlusterFS, and OpenVZ;
- Integrated CI/CD and IaC methodologies using GitLab CI, Terraform, Ansible, and Argo CD;
- Supervised a diverse array of 100 Java/Go microservices, which operated around the clock to process a workload ranging from 2 to 12 thousand requests per second, fulfilling the needs of the Federal Service for the Regulation of the Alcohol Market (FSRAR).
- During periods of reduced activity, crafted custom Rust-based command-line tools, such as: github.com/mbrav/gitraider

Banks Soft Systems (BSS)

Release Engineer / Python Developer https://spitch.ai/

Decreased release build and testing pipelines by more than 300%;

- Integrated automated procedures for building and testing docker containers with varying NLP models and Linux distribution configurations (RHEL, Centos, Redhat, Ubuntu, Rocky) for clients with the help of Bash, Python, Ansible and GithHub Actions;
- Oversaw CVE warnings and dependency security issues in docker images using security scanning tools;
- Performed Code Review for a ML project that uses the Rasa Python framework and a custom service written in Haskell.

Genesis Block 2021-11 – 2022-03

Python and Blockchain Developer

https://genesisblock.ru/eng/

- Designed and developed high-performance APIs using Flask and FastAPI frameworks in Python.
- Effectively maintained and supported projects that integrated smart contracts and other innovative solutions within the Blockchain domain.
- Collaborated with development teams and international clients to ensure a precise understanding of requirements and the efficient execution of projects.
- Implemented cutting-edge development methodologies in Python and adhered to best programming practices, ensuring high-quality code and overall project effectiveness.

Education

Parsons School of Design 2014 − 2018

Design and Technology Bachelor's degree

the https://www.newschool.edu/parsons/bfa-design-technology/

The New School Philosophy

2015 – 2019 Bachelor's degree

2022-04 - 2022-11

A https://www.newschool.edu/

Creative applications of programming in art and design:

Javascript, node.js, Java, C++, Arduino, Raspbery Pi and Linux

Studied Continental Philosophy, Formal Logic, Epistemology,

Ancient Greek Philosophy and German Idealism.